SALAHUDDIN KHAN

Software Developer

Quality-oriented recent college graduate with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science with 2 years of work experience. Aiming to leverage the academic experience and proven knowledge of Software Developing and Android Apps Developing to successfully fill the Software Developer role at your company. Frequently praised as a Hard-Working team player by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

Work Experience

Software Developer

[Dec 2018 - Present]

Tektekies Inc., Calgary, AB

- Responsible for the design, build, deployment, debug & maintenance of Web-Based applications for client and Android apps for Google play store.
- Developed Web based BD Question Bank solution and Android apps Family Tracker and Covid19 Info.
- Tested applications on multiple devices to insure compatibility standards.
- Developed native mobile application using Java/Kotlin and XML/JSON in Android Studio.
- Environment: Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Android Studio, Android Framework, SQLite, Android API's, JDK

Java Developer

[Nov 2012 - May 2014]

Drik ICT Ltd., Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developed web-based bandwidth manager for small ISP.
- Developed Automated Monthly Report System for ISP clients.
- Responsible for deployment, upgrade and maintenance of Monitoring tools.
- Supported, monitored, tested and resolved hardware and Application Level problems.
- Installed new applications, system upgrades, evaluate and install hardware as applicable.

Software Development Skills

- Proficient in Java, C++ and C#.
- Experienced Android Developer
- Expertise in Front End Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP.
- Experience working with CodeIgniter and Spring framework.
- Experience working with REST API and SOAP Web services
- Experience working with MySQL, SQL and MongoDB.

PERSONAL INFO

Address

115 Skyview Point Road, Calgary, AB, T3N 0K4

Phone

+1 (647) 669-6467

E-mail

priomkhan1988@gmail.com

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/md-salahuddin-khan/

Website

www.mskdev.com

SKILLES

Object-oriented design,
Software testing and
debugging,
Data Maintenance,
Problem solving and logical
thinking,
Teamworking
REST API

<u>IDE</u>

Intelili

Very Good

Visual Studio 2019

Good

MS Excel

Very Good

Android Studio

Very Good

GIT(SVN)

. . . .

Education

B.Sc. in Computer Science

[Jun 2015 - Dec 2018]

University of Saskatchewan

Worked as a volunteer at UofS graduation party organizer

B.Sc. in Electrical & Electronics Engineering

[Jan 2007 - Mar 2012]

East West University, Bangladesh

- EX-Member of IEEE
- Cisco IT Ambassador Bangladesh Region.

Projects and Other Accomplishments

Covid19 Info

[Tektekies Inc. – Feb-2020]

- Developed an all-in-one Android App for latest Covid-19 information and news.
- Used JSON data from Live Server that updates daily.
- One-Click Global and Country specific data pulling and analyzing
- Global news feed from different source.
- Used Android Studio, Kotlin, XML, JSON, Retrofit, Moshi, Covid19 API.

Family Tracker

[Tektekies Inc. - Dec-2019]

- Developed an Android App to track friends and family using their phone's GPS location.
- App helps you to keep your love one safe by sending or receiving alarm in danger.
- View real time location and real time Alarm when connected use arrived or leave destination.
- Used Android Studio, Java, XML, JSON, Retrofit, Moshi and Google API.

BD Question Bank

[Tektekies Inc. - Mar-2019]

- Online question bank for Bangladesh Education System to prevent question paper leak.
- Authentication system for the examiner to get the question paper online.
- Add, Edit and delete existing questions.
- Creating random question papers for each board on a specific subject.
- Time restriction to prevent early question paper access.
- Desktop admin system to manage database.
- Used Android Studio, Java, XML, Google API and MySQL.

Lambda Organizer

[UofS - Software Engineering - Oct-2018]

- Developed an all-in-one student organizer app for android devices, complete with a calendar and scheduling system, grade calculator and storage, task management, and timer all with notification utilities.
- The design is alluring in that it is a simple way to organize a complicated school life, with many useful components in the same place.
- Used Android Studio, Java, Google API.

REFERENCES

PERSONAL INFO

Address

115 Skyview Point Road, Calgary, AB, T3N 0K4

Phone

+1 (647) 669-6467

E-mail

priomkhan1988@gmail.com

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/md-salahuddin-khan/

Website

www.mskdev.com